"The left side and the right side
of that country didn't get along,
so they built a wall...
and agreed not to have
dealings with each other."
Don't you think this is pointless, Madam Witch?
What do you mean by pointless?
Those on the two sides of the wall
really do not get along,
and do not want to see each other.
But the wall itself is pointless.
Huh...
We don't want to lose to the other side.
Even with this pointless wall,
we want to brag that
we are better on this side, but...
Do you have any ideas for
what we could do, Madam Witch?
Well, I might.
Mr. Official, do you have a knife?
Hm? I do...
What are you planning to do with that?
This...
Hm?
"This side of the country is great.
By the Witch of the Travels."
What is the meaning of this?
This wall represents the
separation between the two sides,
but it also represents how
this side is wonderful, right?
Huh? Well...
So you should have travelers who
visit carve words into the wall like this.
The more words you have on this side,
the clearer it is that this side is wonderful.
But I don't really like doing things that way...
Oh, speaking of which,
on the other side of the wall,
many travelers have already left their marks!
"After that, I went to
the other side of the wall..."
Oh, speaking of which,
on the other side of the wall,
many travelers have already left their marks!
What?
"...and told them the same thing.
"This side of the country is great."
"By the Witch of the Travels"
"...and told them the same thing.
"This side of the country is great."
"By the Witch of the Travels"
Since then, it became custom for
all travelers who visit that country
to etch words into that wall."
"The Wall Etched by Travelers"
What was the point in having
travelers carve words into the wall?
Well...
Maybe it was like a popularity contest.
Popularity contest?
They want to brag that they're better
than the people on the other side of the wall.
To be able to say that there are
more words on their side praising them.
So then, in the end, which side was better?
Which side of the wall had more words on it?
You'll have to go see with your own eyes.
Yeah!
When I become a witch and travel...
Definitely!
Wow, this is amazing.
"This country's the best!"
"I've never been to such a great country!"
"We'll be getting married soon!"
"Best traveling buds forever."
"Friends forever!"
"This country is as great as our muscles."
Oh, excuse me, but...
You're the witch from the
United Magic Association, right?
I'm Saya, the Charcoal Witch.
Nice to meet you!
I've heard about this wall,
but it really is amazing, huh?
You can really see how many
people have visited this country.
Our request for you is to do
something about this wall.
Do something?
It's been more than ten years
since a traveling witch
suggested we have visitors
etch messages into the wall.
But recently, people have been losing interest,
so we want to do something new.
Something new, huh?
It already seems pretty great to me, though.
The wall etched by travelers, huh?
Hm? Traveler?
Mister! Can I borrow a knife, please?
S-Sure...
...ve Mi... na... lo... Ela...
I ...ove ...iss ...lain... I love Miss Elaina...
Miss Elaina... Miss Elaina... Miss Elaina...
Wh-What are you doing?
This wall isn't a place for you
to carve your carnal desires!
What are you saying, Mister?
This is very important!
What's so important about that?
This wall is here for travelers to
carve how wonderful this country is!
Oh, about that rule--
Why don't you try changing it starting today?
What?!
Starting today, make it so the people
of this country can also carve into it.
They can carve their passionate
feelings about the person they like,
or their hopes for the future,
or "I love Miss Elaina!" or something.
What's the reason for doing that?
Hm? I mean, you're the ones
who made this wall, right?
So shouldn't it be here for your sakes?
Turn it from a wall for travelers
into a wall that will help you
fix your eyes straight ahead.
I see...
Thanks for this.
Well, I'm off then!
Hm? Right...
I've got a job on the
other side of the wall, too!
Why was my heart swelling
with expectation on that day?
The answer is--
Because I was about to visit the country
with words etched into its wall
that appeared in The Adventures of Niké,
a book that influenced me greatly.
There's no wall here!
Welcome! Cheap wall pieces for sale!
How about some mementos of your trip?
This isn't just debris!
It's debris from the famous wall!
--No, it is just debris...
--It's rare! Rare!
Oh, you're the traveling witch!
It's been what, more than ten years?
You know who I am?
Your face looks younger than back then...?
It's true.
Looking carefully, your chest is different, too.
What, you're not her?
Too bad.
Well, are you two officials in this country?
Or are you just regular wrinkly old men?
We are indeed officials.
But we are also wrinkly old men.
Then, this is perfect.
Will you tell me why you tore down the wall?
This is the explanation I was given--
At the advice of a witch who visited
this country a little before I had,
"I love you! Forever!"
At the advice of a witch who visited
this country a little before I had,
"I love you! Forever!"
the people of this country started
carving whatever they wanted on the wall.
"I hate that guy"
the people of this country started
carving whatever they wanted on the wall.
"The king has donkey ears"
the people of this country started
carving whatever they wanted on the wall.
At first, they were happy with that,
"I am a fallen angel appearing
from the deepest darkness"
At first, they were happy with that,
but as days and then weeks passed...
What does forever mean, anyway?
We already broke up!
I wrote something crazy when I was drunk!
--What the hell? Who wrote
these insults about me?
--People say, "What happens
on a trip, stays on a trip."
--What the hell? Who wrote
these insults about me?
--But the words etched by the people
of the country stayed with them,
--What is this? It's so embarrassing!
and became embarrassing memories.
And so, they decided to tear down the wall.
Before they knew it,
the resentment they felt toward
the people on the other side
didn't matter anymore.
Before, everyone thought they were better
than those on the other side of the wall--
But with the embarrassing
things they wrote themselves,
they realized that wasn't the case.
In the end, this country didn't need a wall.
We were all the same in every way.
From now on, I suppose we will live
peacefully in our ordinary country.
Huh...
Well then, Madam Witch. Please excuse us.
Um--
Before the wall was torn down,
which side had more praises etched into it?
Isn't it obvious?
It was the same for both sides.
The same?
We started off as the same country.
And we all worked hard
so we wouldn't lose to the other side.
Why didn't you realize
that the same growth was
happening on the other side of the wall?
In order to convince
ourselves that we were better,
we didn't want to look on
the other side of the wall.
Yeah, that went for all of us.
"This side of the country is great."
"By the Witch of the Travels"
I'm sure this worked out for the best.
A country isn't for tourists or travelers,
but for those who live there.
It's too bad I couldn't see the wall, though.
I wonder if Niké carved those words
thinking the wall would be gone in the future.
No, there's no way.
Cute witch, how about a piece
of the wall as a souvenir?
Well, I suppose as a memento,
I'll take... this one.
Thanks!
Please come again!
"Elai..."
Elai...?
Yes, this year's grapes look
like they're ripening well, too.
I'm sure they'll make delicious wine.
I'm looking forward to that.
Step, step...
Grandpa!
Look, look!
I'm going to wear this for the
Grape-Throwing Festival that's coming up!
Oh, it looks good on you.
Hey, Grandpa, how did the
Grape-Throwing Festival start?
How? Well...
A long, long time ago,
when this village was still split
into That Village and This Village,
and all we did was fight,
a witch came to visit during the grape harvest.
"The Grape-Stomping Girl"
Welcome to This Village.
"This Village"?
Yes! Our village is called "This Village,"
and on the other side
of the road is "That Village."
The two villages, This and That,
are famous for wine, right?
Indeed! Wine is a local specialty.
Madam Witch, do you like wine?
I've never had any.
That's why I came here.
Oh?
I wanted my first taste of alcohol
to be something very delicious.
I see. Then, you were
right to come to This Village.
The wine from This Village is so delicious,
the wine from That Village
and elsewhere cannot compare!
It is truly a wine made by God!
It's that good?
So, is that the wine you boast of?
Gulp! No, it's not...
This wine is from That Village.
I-It's outrageous!
That Village has started doing this!
"Grape-stomping maiden,
Rosemary, from That Village.
'I lovingly stepped on the grapes.'"
With this wonderful label
of the lovely Rosemary,
That Village is increasing their sales.
Huh.
And they make it seem like Rosemary
is the place of origin of the wine--
"Place of origin"?
That's right.
Not the manufacturer, but the place of origin?
Because making her the place of
origin will tempt people to buy it.
"Tempt"?
In other words, appealing to fetishes
is also important in business.
Huh, so it's selling well, is it?
Just because a cute girl
is stepping lovingly on it!
"Stepping lovingly"...
Then, why doesn't This Village
try competing with them
by getting a cute girl to do
the, "stepping lovingly" thing?
Well said!
That's exactly what we should do!
If we get a sweet maiden
to step lovingly on our grapes,
then we can win!
So, Madam Witch, will you do the honors?
Well?
Huh?
Everybody! Madam Witch said
she'll step lovingly on our grapes!
I can't believe such a cute witch
will step lovingly on our grapes!
All right! Step on me, too!
--Um, what am I...
--Hurry up and get ready!
Hey, wait--
Why do I have to wear this?
Grape-stomping maidens
must all wear these clothes!
It makes them more tempting.
"Tempting"?
Ready, go!
Oh my, what might you be doing?
Hello, Chief of This Village that's dying out.
Y-You...! The shiningly beautiful Rosemary!
Rosemary...!
Oh? What might that bottle
you're holding to your chest be?
Gulp!
Might it be wine from my label?
Could you be a fan of mine?
F-Fan? O-Of course not...
I can sign the label if you'd like.
Sign?!
And? Who in the world is this undersized
girl in grape-stomping maiden clothes?
I'm a traveling witch.
Oh? A witch?
Oh, I see. You can't beat me,
so you're planning to have this
thin girl step lovingly on some grapes?
"Thin," you say?
Her face is just okay, too.
"Just okay"?
Her figure is like that of a child's.
"Like a child's"?!
No, not "like a child"--she is a child.
You can't beat me by having a child
like this step lovingly on grapes!
--Well then, excuse me.
--Step! Step! Step! Step!
Chief, I will do it.
Huh?
I will be the grape-stomping maiden!
Yeah!
--Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die!
--Step! Step! Step! Step! Step! Step!
--Step... Step... Step... Step...
--Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die!
--Step! Step! Step! Step! Step! Step!
I'm beat...
Madam Witch, good work.
I feel like I stomped a lot of grapes today.
How much wine do you think it'll make?
Let's see... maybe about half a cask?
That's it? Even though I stomped that much?
It's so hard being a grape-stomping maiden...
How much of that wine is being sold?
A lot! Hundreds, maybe
even thousands of bottles!
Do you mean to say that Rosemary is
stomping grapes from morning until night
to make that many bottles of wine?
Don't you think it's strange?
It is...
--Step! Step! Step! Step!
--Step harder on those grapes.
--Don't you want to sell
wine with my label on it?
--Step! Step! Step! Step!
--Come on! Come on!
--What in the world...
--Step! Step! Step! Step!
--The wine wasn't lovingly
stepped on by Rosemary...!
--Step! Step! Step! Step!
--Well, it's obvious now.
Then--
This means the point of
origin is fraudulent, isn't it?
This is a case that could be brought to court!
Step...
Crap...
We're found out, huh?
We were selling so many, too...
It's kind of amazing we weren't
found out until now, though.
Rosemary's wine... was stomped
by those strong men over there...?
What's the big deal
about lying about the origin?
There's no difference once you drink it!
I see. It's my first time drinking wine,
but it really is delicious.
What's important are the feelings!
Even if it tastes the same,
it was important for it to
be stepped on by Rosemary...
That's... That's what fetishism is!
Shut up! Don't complain about Rosemary!
Be quiet!
Bastard!
What are you doing to our chief?!
Oh, really, what am I to do with you all?
And then? And then what happened?
Everyone took those grape bullets...
...and was knocked out.
By the time we woke up,
the witch had already left.
And that's the story of how
the Grape-Throwing Festival began.
It was a good way to release stress,
so it became tradition
to have it during the harvest.
And before we knew it, the two villages
had stopped fighting and become one.
Really? Then we need to thank that witch!
Yes, we do...
What happened to Rosemary?
That's--
That's?
Well, that's a story for another time.
I think it's about time we had lunch.
Go wash your hands.
Okay!
Really, ripening well...
Tempting me no matter how old...
Hey, good work! Let's have lunch now.
Okay!